Looks delicious.
看起来好好吃
The juicy Hakone Sanroku Beef.
肉汁欲滴的箱根山麓牛肉
Look at this one! Fresh and extravagant seafood platter!
看这个 新鲜豪华海鲜盘
I like this room with the open bath.
我喜欢这家有露天温泉的
I agree.
赞成
We've been working for five years, so it's time to treat ourselves.
我们都工作五年了 该慰劳自己一下
That's right, we're working hard.
没错 我们工作那么认真
Then Natsuko, you'll be the coordinator, since this was your idea.
奈津子 你出的主意 你来统筹
-What? Me? -Thanks, Natsuko.
-我吗？ -谢谢 奈津子
Roger!
了解
Let's talk and drink all night to release our stress.
我们聊天喝通宵宣泄压力
I'll save up lots of horrible stories about my boss.
我会积攒很多我上司的可怕事迹
I can talk all night about the awful Section Chief at my workplace.
我可以抱怨一整夜 办公室里那个讨厌的课长
I can't wait to try the hot spring.
我迫不及待想泡温泉
This is delicious!
好好吃
This has the perfect flavor.
这个调味最完美了
This has the perfect consistency.
这个口感最完美了
I love watching you eat.
我喜欢看着你吃饭
I can tell you enjoy it.
看得出来你真的很喜欢吃
As you get older your appetite decreases, right?
年纪越大胃口越差 对吧？
So it's quality over quantity.
所以要重质不重量
That's why I'm so particular about delicious cuisine.
就是因为这样我才偏好美食
I agree, Mr. Soma.
我同意 相马先生
We're so like-minded.
我们志同道合
Yeah!
耶
Oh?
什么？
Where's Hanasaki… I mean, where's your daughter?
花琦呢？我是说 你女儿呢？
-She's out drinking with her colleagues. -Her colleagues?
-她和同事出去喝酒了 -她同事？
She gets together with those girls pretty often.
她经常和那几个女孩在一起
I see.
这样啊
They're probably releasing their stress by talking bad
她们大概在说办公室和上司的坏话
about their workplace and boss.
来释放压力
Women love doing things like that.
女人喜欢做那种事
Yes.
对
But Mr. Soma, I'm sure no one ever talks bad about you.
不过 相马先生 我相信不会有人说你的坏话
-That's not true. -No way, Mr. Soma.
-不可能 -可是 相马先生
You're the ideal boss.
你是理想上司
No, no.
才不是那样
No, no. My boss is a pretty nice guy,
才不是那样 我上司人是挺好的
but he's not motivated, and he's also unreliable.
可是他没动力 又靠不住
He's not the ideal boss at all.
完全不是理想上司
Mai, you've become like an old man.
舞 你变得像个老头了
-What? -I was thinking the same thing.
-什么？ -我也有同样的想法
-Your mannerism and the way you speak. -No way…
-你的习惯动作和说话方式 -不可能
I'm alone with him at work, so maybe he's rubbing off on me.
工作时就我跟他一起 可能被他潜移默化影响到
Did you hear that Nanami is going to start a new job in June?
七海要在6月换新工作 你们听说了吗？
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的假的？ -真的
-It's sad to see our colleagues leave.
-看到同事离职真难过 -对呀
What if I'm the only one left.
万一只剩我一个 要怎么办？
No one will give us a goodbye party.
不会有人帮我们办离职派对
In that case, everyone who was in the same employee training class
那样的话 参加同一梯新进员工训练的人
should all quit together. No?
都应该一起辞职 不是吗？
What?
什么啊？
Employee training class makes me nostalgic.
好怀念新进员工训练
We couldn't even count bills properly back then.
那时我们连钞票都数不好
We just happened to be in the same class, and we've been friends since.
我们刚好在同一个班 从那之后就一直是好朋友
Yeah.
没错
This monthly colleague dinner has been going on for a long time.
每个月一次的聚餐持续好久了
Though we lost some members.
尽管我们失去了几个成员
Well, all of us here are late in the game.
这里每个人都是后段班的
What? Did I say something I shouldn't have?
怎么了？我说了不该说的吗？
Let's raise our glasses.
我们来举杯
To what?
敬什么？
Cheers to our colleagues who are working hard!
敬我们工作认真的同事
Cheers.
干杯
That charged me with power to work hard tomorrow.
我充满能量了 明天要努力工作
Mai, it's amazing that you're working at the headquarters now.
舞 真没想到你现在在总部工作
Not at all.
才没有
Branch inspection is a job that's hated by the branches.
分行稽核是受到分行讨厌的工作
-But you're doing your best, right? -I wonder.
-可是你尽力了 对吧？ -我不知道
-And you, Natsuko? -Hm?
-奈津子 你呢？ -嗯？
You haven't given up on the general management position, right?
你还没有放弃综合管理职 对吧？
Hm…
嗯
I still can't understand why
我还是不懂为什么
you never passed the examination.
你总是无法通过那个考试
You're writing your name down, right?
你没忘记在考卷上写名字吧？
-I wrote it down. -Really?
-我写了 -真的假的？
I'm so envious of you, Mai. You're always so positive.
舞 我好羡慕你 你总是那么乐观
-That's not true. -Really?
-才不是那样 -真的吗？
Yes.
真的
Maybe I'll buy something on the way back.
我可能会在回去的路上买点东西
TRUTH ABOUT THE MEGA BANK T
（大型Ｔ银行的真相）
BEAUTIFUL FEMALE BANKER EXPOSES THE HIDDEN FACE OF AN ELITE BANKER!
（美女银行职员揭发 精英银行员的隐藏面目）
We're in trouble.
大事不妙了
-We're in trouble. -Good morning, Mr. Shibasaki.
-大事不妙了 -早安 芝崎次长
Good morning. What's going on this morning?
早安 今天早上怎么了？
Was the convenience store out of your favorite chocolate?
你最爱的便利商店巧克力卖完了吗？
Yesterday, it was because the cutlet at the cafeteria was too thin.
昨天是因为自助食堂的炸肉排太薄
How can you guys be so carefree?
你们两个怎么能这么悠闲快活？
Haven't you seen this?
你们没看这个吗？
-What? -Huh?
-什么？ -啊？
"The hidden face of an elite banker?"
“精英银行员的隐藏面目”
"Sexual harassment by a branch manager?"
“受到分行经理的性骚扰”？
What?
什么？
Mega bank T…
“大型Ｔ银行”
This picture is clearly our bank.
这张照片明显是我们银行
This ID…
这个工作证
It's our bank.
是我们银行的
That's why I said that we're in trouble.
所以我才说我们有麻烦了
I see…
原来如此
"The accusation was made by a female teller in her twenties working at
“提出指控的是一位 在东京Ｔ银行工作的
Bank T located in the city."
二十多岁的女银行员”
"Calls me into his office and touches me"?
“把我叫进他的办公室后抚摸我”？
"Holds my hand in the elevator"?
“在电梯里握我的手”？
"Tried to kiss me"?
“试图亲吻我”？
This is despicable!
这太卑鄙了
How scary.
好可怕
It's preposterous to be doing that in the workplace!
在工作场所做那种事太荒谬
If it was me, I would've punched him.
换作是我 我一定揍他
Yes, you would.
你一定会的 花琦
-Hanasaki won't have to worry. -What?
-花琦不必担心这个 -什么？
Do you think anyone would sexually harass Hanasaki?
再说了 你认为会有人 对花琦性骚扰吗？
-Very true. -Right?
-那倒是真的 -对吧？
The remark you just made is sexual harassment too.
你们刚刚的发言也算性骚扰
Really?
是这样吗？
Branch Inspection.
是 稽核班
Good morning, Director Karashima.
早安 辛岛部长
What?
什么？
Soma. Hanasaki.
相马 花琦
-This is Assistant General Manager Omae. -I'm Omae.
-这位是人事部的大前次长 -我是大前
-I'm Soma from Branch Inspection. -I'm Hanasaki.
-我是稽核班的相马 -我是花琦
Did you two read this?
两位看过这个了吗？
Yes.
看过了
In order to solve this issue as quickly as possible,
为了尽快解决这个问题
the Branch Managing Department
我们分行管理部
will cooperate with HR.
将和人事部合作
I want you to find out who this female employee is.
我要你们查出这位女职员是谁
Find? But how…
查出？可是要怎么查？
She probably said this in order to get some money,
她说这些大概是想拿钱
but this is unacceptable.
不过这是不会被接受的
But she is claiming that she was--
但是她宣称她是…
It's something written by a gossip magazine.
这都是八卦杂志写的
Sexual harassment at our bank
我们银行怎么可能有性骚扰？
is obviously nonsense.
显然是胡说八道
But…
但是…
Come in.
请进
-Excuse me. -Mr. Shindo.
-打扰了 -真藤常务
What happened?
有什么事吗？
How's the investigation regarding the female employee in the article?
周刊说的女职员调查得如何了？
We just assigned that task to these two.
刚把这个任务交给这两位
What? To Branch Inspection?
什么？交给稽核班？
Can we trust this task to them?
我们能放心将这个任务交给你们吗？
They will be fine.
他们没问题的
They're a reliable pair that has resolved many problems at the branches.
他们是可以信赖的搭档 已经解决过许多分行问题
But this is different
可是这一次
from the small problems that Branch Inspection has been dealing with.
与稽核班处理的小问题不一样
In order to maintain our bank's trust, we must avoid any scandal.
为了维持本行信誉 必须避免任何丑闻
But as for this case,
但是这个案子
there are things that can only be discussed between women.
有些事只能女人之间讨论
So sending her would be appropriate.
所以派她去是恰当的
I see.
这样啊
You will find her, right?
你会找到她 对吧？
I will do everything I can.
我会尽我的全力
Everything you can?
你的全力？
I mean…
不 我是说…
I will definitely find her.
我绝对会找到她
I see. Definitely.
“绝对会” 是吧？
Yes.
是
If you find anything out, contact me right away.
查到任何事 立刻联系我
I understand.
了解
Yes, sir.
是
Why did you say "definitely"?
你为什么说“绝对会”？
Think about what that means for us.
你也考虑一下我的立场
-I'm sorry. I couldn't resist… -You can never resist.
-对不起 不小心就… -你老是不小心
You can't resist saying or doing something.
“不小心就说了” “不小心就做了”
Do you know how much trouble I've gone through because you can't resist?
你知道因为你的不小心 让我经历了多少麻烦吗？
I'm sorry I couldn't resist…
对不起 我不小心就…
-See? -Oh.
看吧？
Don't say that starting today.
从今天起不要再说“不小心”了
-What? -Think about it.
-什么？ -想想看
How many thousands of female employees do you think there are within the city?
你认为我们银行在东京 有几千名女职员？
Finding one particular person among all of them,
从这些人之中找到特定的一位
is like finding a needle in a haystack.
就像大海捞针
But you said, "I will definitely find her."
你却说你绝对会找到她
What we know from this article is that
从文章中我们知道
she is a teller in her twenties, who is working within the city.
她是在东京工作的二十几岁的柜员
How are we supposed to
我们该怎样
narrow down the suspects.
才能缩小嫌疑人范围？
MS. A IS A TELLER IN HER TWENTIES WORKING AT A BRANCH IN THE CITY
（Ａ小姐是二十几岁的柜员 在东京某分行服务）
MS. A / IN HER TWENTIES
（Ａ小姐二十几岁）
I got it.
有了
Let's start by looking at pictures of tellers within the city.
我们从看东京柜员的照片开始
Why?
为什么？
Because it said, "beautiful employee."
因为上面写“漂亮的职员”
Mr. Soma, you really are
相马先生
an old man.
你真的是老头呢
I was only joking.
我只是开个玩笑
How about we ask the publisher?
我们去问出版社如何？
They'll never tell us.
他们才不会告诉我们
Moreover, they'll write, "Tokyo Daiichi Bank came to
而且下一期还会写“东京第一银行
the publishing department to ask about Ms. A,"
到出版社询问Ａ小姐是谁”
in next week's article to make fun of us.
这种文章嘲笑我们
You're right.
你说得对
Let's start by searching for certain employees.
总之 我们先从递交过辞呈的
-Those who've given notice. -What?
-女职员找起吧 -什么？
Selling the company you work for to a magazine
出卖公司给周刊
means they're ready to leave.
表示她准备离职了
I see. I'll have HR make a list for us.
原来如此 我请人事部列一张表给我们
Okay, thanks.
好 谢谢
Among the tellers in their twenties who are working within the city,
在东京工作的二十几岁的柜员中
12 of them have handed in their letter of resignation.
有12位递交了辞职书
That's a lot. What's the reason?
好多啊 辞职理由是什么？
Marriage, giving birth, studying abroad, change of occupation, and so forth.
结婚、生子、出国留学、换工作等等
Oh yeah, Hanasaki.
对了 花琦
-I want you to do the questioning. -What?
-这次问话由你来做 -什么？
We'll be talking to women…
这次要和女职员谈话
Only you can do it.
只有你能胜任
Director Karashima said that too.
辛岛部长也那么说
I see.
这样啊
I understand.
好 我知道了
This is going to be a really big hassle.
这会是非常大的麻烦
-Did you say something? -No, nothing.
-你在说什么？ -没什么
SOUTH SHINJUKU BRANCH
（南新宿分行）
I'm offended!
太过分了
Do I look like a whistleblower who would
我像是会为我工作的银行
trouble the bank that I was working at?
带来麻烦的举报者吗？
No, not at all.
绝对不是
We are just asking everyone who is leaving,
我们会询问每个将要离职的人
just to make sure.
只是为了确定而已
Do you think I'm leaving because I hate this company?
你以为我离职是因为讨厌这家公司？
That's just ridiculous!
真是太荒谬了
Oh… um… I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
It's a long road ahead of us.
眼前是条漫漫长路呢
Hey Hanasaki, there's a great
花琦 那边
curry restaurant over there.
有一家不错的咖哩餐厅
We don't have time for that today.
今天没那个时间
DENENCHOFU BRANCH
（田园调布分行）
I wonder who that teller is.
我想知道那个柜员是谁
I'm so curious.
我好好奇
-Yes… -I had thoughts on who it might be.
-这样啊 -我认为可能是
Maybe beautiful Aiko from the Marunouchi Branch.
丸之内分行的美女爱子
-She had quit already though. -Um…
-但是她已经辞职了 -嗯
Then how about
那会不会是
the girl in Yokohama?
在横滨的那个女生？
It's within the city…
是在东京里
Then what about the girl at the Hachioji Branch?
那么八王子市分行的那个女生呢？
How about the Beyoncé look-alike at the Tama Branch?
多摩市分行那个长得像碧昂丝的呢？
What about the Higashimurayama Branch?
还是东村山市分行？
MUKOJIMA BRANCH
（向岛分行）
Do you suspect me?
你们是在怀疑我吗？
No, we're asking other people,
不是 我们也问了其他人
so it's not just you.
不是只问你一个人
But you didn't call the other older tellers…
可是你们没有叫其他年长的柜员
Oh, well… um…
嗯 那个…
Please don't cry.
请你别哭
What are you doing here?
你们在这里做什么？
-You didn't call the branch manager. -I'm very sorry.
-你们没通知分行经理 -非常抱歉
But you seemed very busy.
因为你好像非常忙碌
I hear that you came to investigate that article.
我听说你们是来调查那篇报导的
Yes… oh, well…
是… 不是
Then what?
然后呢？
You think I'm sexually harassing my staff?
你们认为我性骚扰我的下属？
No, we don't suspect you…
不 我们没有怀疑你
Do I look like someone who would do something that despicable?
我像是会做那种卑劣的事的人吗？
But sometimes looks can be deceiving.
但是有时候外表会骗人
-Right? -That's right… what?
-对吧？ -没错 什么？
You're doubting me!
你们怀疑我 是吧？
Thank you for your support. Come on, let's go.
感谢您的协助 我们快走
I'm so tired.
好累
I'm so hungry.
好饿
We didn't have time to eat lunch.
我们没时间吃午餐
But we didn't produce any results.
却没有查出任何结果
Did you learn anything?
你们有什么发现吗？
Nothing in particular.
没什么特别的
None of the tellers seemed to fit the bill.
那些柜员都不符合
Will you be able to find her like this?
这样做有办法找到她吗？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Oh, jeez…
真是的
It's unforgivable that she's working another day
她为了赚钱出卖公司
when she sold out our company to get money.
却还继续工作 真是不可原谅
Um… I've been wondering why this Ms. A
我很想知道为什么这位Ａ小姐
is being blamed for everything.
会承担所有的责备
-Isn't that unfair? -Hanasaki.
-那不公平 不是吗？ -花琦
The manager that sexually harassed her
分行经理对她性骚扰
is the main problem.
才是最主要的问题
Do you believe what's written in this magazine?
你相信这本周刊里写的东西吗？
Generally speaking,
一般来说
most women who cry about being sexually harassed
大部分哭喊受到性骚扰的女人
are just exaggerating things and making a big deal out of nothing.
只是夸张生事、无风起浪
I feel sorry for the boss.
我替那些上司感到难过
This Ms. A,
这位Ａ小姐
must be a good-for-nothing girl.
肯定是个一无是处的女孩
With all… due…
恕我直…
Either way,
不管怎样
find this female teller as soon as possible.
尽快找到这个女柜员
Understand?
懂了吗？
Yes.
是
That Omae gets me so mad.
那个大前次长真让人火大
I can't believe someone in HR would say that.
不敢相信人事部的人会说出那种话
-Yeah. -Mai.
-没错 -舞
This bank with
这家发生性骚扰的银行
sexual harassment isn't your bank, is it?
不是你们银行吧？
It says Bank T right here…
这里说是Ｔ银行
-Keep it on the down-low. -It is?
-不要声张 -果然是你们啊？
Your voice is too loud.
太大声了
Mai, I hope you weren't sexually harassed
舞 你在当柜员时
when you were a teller.
没有受到性骚扰吧？
-No, don't worry. -Really?
-没有 别担心 -真的吗？
Don't worry.
放心吧
No man would sexually harass her.
没有男人会对她性骚扰
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
Oh… no, that came out wrong.
不 我那样说不对
I didn't mean it that way.
我不是那个意思
-You're right. -Dad?
-你说的对 -爸
Because if you do anything like that to her, she'll break
因为要是你对她做出那种事
a bone or two.
她会打断你几根骨头
I agree.
没错
-Mr. Kozo. -It's hot.
-幸三先生 -好烫
But Mr. Omae might have a valid point.
不过大前先生说对了一点
Everything written in these magazines isn't guaranteed to be true.
周刊写的东西不一定全是对的
You're right, but…
你说的对 但是…
-What? -Well.
-怎么？ -我…
I read that article over and over again.
读了这篇报导好几遍
She says, "Every day, I was scared of what he would do to me,
她说：“我每天都害怕 他会对我做出什么事
but I couldn't afford to take a day off,"
但是我无力请一天的假”
or "I just need to bear it."
或者“我只需要忍受”
I think Ms. A
我认为Ａ小姐
is earnest and has a strong sense of responsibility
是诚恳、有强烈责任感的人
Yeah.
对
I don't think someone like that would lie just to make money.
我不认为那样的人会为了赚钱而说谎
That makes sense too.
那样说也有道理
So she must have been pushed beyond her limit.
所以她肯定是被逼到极限
She was alone without anyone around her that she can confide in…
孤立无援 身边没有可以倾诉的人
If that's true, I feel very bad for her.
如果真是那样 我替她感到难过
THE WHISTLEBLOWER WHO LEAKED THE STORY
（透露性骚扰故事给周刊的）
ABOUT THE SEXUAL HARASSMENT IS
（举报者Ａ小姐是…）
We're in trouble!
大事不妙了
What is it now?
今天又怎么了？
This email was sent to the President.
这个电子邮件送到总裁那里
Let me see.
让我看看
"The whistleblower who leaked the story about the sexual harassment
“透露性骚扰故事给周刊的举报者
is Natsuko Kawashima from the Kyobashi Branch."
Ａ小姐是京桥分行的川岛奈津子”
Let me see that.
那个让我看一下
Natsuko…
奈津子？
You know her?
你认识她？
She's my colleague. Who would do such a horrible thing…
她跟我一起入职的 谁会做出这么可怕的事呢？
Can you go to the Kyobashi Branch?
你们可以去一趟京桥分行吗？
Mr. Shibasaki, you believe this email?
芝崎次长相信这个邮件？
Well…
那个…
This is obviously a prank.
这很明显是恶作剧
If she's Ms. A, she would have
如果她是Ａ小姐
confided in me before doing something like this.
应该会在做出这种事前找我倾诉
She never said she was harassed.
但她从来没说过她受到骚扰
I see…
这样啊
But since this email was sent to us,
但是既然这个都传给我们了
we can't ignore it.
我们就不能置之不理
Please go talk to her.
请去和她谈谈
I understand.
我明白
Let's go.
走吧
Okay…
是
What is it? You look so lost.
怎么一副失了魂的样子？
It's nothing.
没什么
You're sure it's not Ms. Kawashima, right?
你确定不是川岛小姐 对吧？
That's right.
那当然
I believe that, but…
我相信是那样 可是…
But if by any chance, Natsuko was
可是如果万一是奈津子
being sexually harassed…
受到性骚扰的话…
KYOBASHI BRANCH
（京桥分行）
This email
其实
was sent to our President.
总裁的信箱收到这封电子邮件
THE WHISTLEBLOWER IS NATSUKO NAGASHIMA OF THE KYOBASHI BRANCH
（举报者Ａ小姐是 京桥分行的川岛奈津子）
Ms. Kawashima?
川岛小姐？
Of course, this email could be a prank.
当然 这个电子邮件可能是恶作剧
But we wanted to make sure.
但是我们想确认
I've known her ever since I was a Deputy Manager
我当副经理时就认识她
but she's not someone who would do something like this.
不过她不是会做这种事的人
Of course, I've never sexually harassed her either.
当然 我也不曾对她性骚扰
Oh, yes…
这当然
How are Ms. Kawashima's work ethics?
川岛小姐的敬业态度如何？
She's a competent and a trustworthy employee.
她是能干又值得信赖的员工
Is it possible to talk with Ms. Kawashima?
我们可以和川岛小姐谈谈吗？
Yes.
好
-Mr. Soma. -Yeah?
-相马先生 -什么事？
Can I talk to her privately?
我可以单独跟她谈吗？
Of course.
交给你了
Thank you.
谢谢你
Excuse me.
打扰了
Mai…
舞
The person from headquarters, is you?
总部派来的人是你啊？
Yeah.
是
You know about that
你知道周刊的
magazine article, right?
那篇报导吧？
Branch Inspection is in charge of that case.
我们稽核班负责那个案子
And…
还有
we received this email today at headquarters.
我们今天在总部收到这个电子邮件
I'm sure it's just a prank,
我相信那只是恶作剧
but we had to come and hear things out.
但是我们必须过来听你的说法
It was me.
是我
I'm the one that sent this email.
我就是发这封电子邮件的人
What?
什么？
Why?
为什么呢？
I wanted them to find out as soon as possible, that I am
我想要他们尽快发现
Ms. A in that article.
周刊说的Ａ小姐就是我
Natsuko…
奈津子
you were sexually harassed?
你受到性骚扰？
Branch Manager Iwaki?
是井胁经理？
The branch manager before Branch Manager Iwaki.
是在井胁经理之前的经理
Who is it?
那是谁？
Assistant General Manager Omae from HR.
人事部的大前次长
What?
什么？
THE WHISTLEBLOWER IS NATSUKO NAGASHIMA OF THE KYOBASHI BRANCH
（举报者Ａ小姐是 京桥分行的川岛奈津子）
What is this?
这是怎么回事？
TRUTH ABOUT THE MEGA BANK T
（大型Ｔ银行的真相）
This article is about me?
这篇文章说的是我？
Damn it.
可恶
That woman…
那个女人
How dare she do this to me!
竟敢对我做这种事
Assistant General Manager Omae…
大前次长…
Is everything written in that article
周刊中写的东西
really true?
都是真的？
Everything he did to me
他对我所做的一切
is true.
都是真的
Good work.
辛苦了
At first, I thought I was thinking too much of it.
一开始 我认为是我想太多了
But when I didn't say anything…
可是当我什么都不说时
his harassment escalated.
他的骚扰变本加厉
But if it was just sexual harassment,
但是如果只是性骚扰
I would have endured it, no matter how frustrating it was.
不论多痛苦 我都会忍受
What happened?
发生了什么事？
Remember how I took the exam
记得去年我参加
for the general management position last year?
那个综合管理职考试吗？
He took me out for dinner the night before the exam.
考前那个晚上 他请我出去吃晚餐
EXAM FOR THE GENERAL MANAGERIAL POSITION
（综合管理职测验说明）
I'll be writing the letter of recommendation
推荐信会由分行经理来写
so don't worry.
你不用担心
Thank you.
麻烦您了
I reserved a room.
我订了一个房间
It'll be for your own good.
这是为了你好
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I'll be leaving.
我要走了
EXAM RESULT FAILED
（测验结果：未通过）
It's too bad you failed.
可惜你没通过
This wouldn't have happened
如果你肯听我的
if you had listened to me.
就不会发生这种事
Is this because
难道是因为
I turned down your offer the other day?
那天我拒绝你的要求吗？
No way…
不可能
I will report this to HR.
我要向人事部举报
That's useless.
没用的
Between a female employee,
女职员
and a branch manager,
和分行经理之间
who will they believe?
他们会相信谁？
That's horrible.
太过分了
You failed the exam because Mr. Omae got mad
你没通过测验 是因为大前先生心生不满
and didn't write a good recommendation?
在推荐信里恶意诋毁吗？
That's so unfair.
这太差劲了
But the branch manager is the one who evaluates
但是负责职员人事考核的
the employees.
是分行经理
But still,
就算是这样
using his authority
他利用职权
to do what he wants with his subordinates is unforgivable.
对下属为所欲为 真不可原谅
Hey,
喂
Natsuko.
奈津子
Why didn't you tell me?
你遭遇到那些事情
That you were going through that.
为什么不告诉我？
Even if you had told me,
就算你告诉了我
it might not have solved anything.
问题也许还是无法解决
But…
可是…
I could have listened to you.
我可以听你诉说
I could've been your support.
我可以当你的支柱
Hey.
喂
We're friends, right?
我们是朋友 对吧？
Then why…
那为什么…
I'm sorry.
对不起
I couldn't tell you,
我无法对你开口
because you're my friend.
因为你是我的朋友
I didn't want you to know that
我不想要你知道
I was being sexually harassed.
我受到性骚扰
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry I wasn't able to realize it.
都怪我没有发现
THE WHISTLEBLOWER IS NATSUKO NAGASHIMA OF THE KYOBASHI BRANCH
（举报者Ａ小姐是 京桥分行的川岛奈津子）
This email was sent to the President?
这个电子邮件发给了总裁？
Yes. We have no idea who would send such a thing.
对 我们不晓得是谁发的
It's nothing but a prank.
那只是恶作剧
How can you be sure?
你怎么能肯定？
Oh, well…
这个…
Tell this Ms. Natsuko Kawashima to come to
请这位川岛奈津子小姐
headquarters tomorrow.
明天到总部来
-Yes. -I'll talk with her directly.
-是 -我直接和她谈
Yes.
是
Now that it's come to this,
既然到了这个地步
we have to investigate all the facts.
不得不调查所有事实
And remove Branch Inspection from this case.
还有 让稽核班退出这个案子
What?
什么？
Conventional sense of justice, and sound argument
传统的正义感和合理的论点
can get in the way sometimes.
有时候会造成妨碍
I was planning to forget everything
我打算忘掉所有事情
because Mr. Omae transferred to
因为1月份 大前先生
headquarters in January.
调去了总部
But when I went to headquarters for training the other day…
但是那天我去总部受训时…
Mr. Omae, we will process this.
大前先生 这个我们会处理
-Thank you. -Okay.
-谢谢你 -好的
Kawashima.
川岛
Long time no see.
好久不见
Yes.
是
Are you planning to take the exam for the general management position?
你还没放弃综合管理职考试？
I'm probably
我大概会
going to be in charge of the interviews.
负责面试的部分
I couldn't understand why someone
我不明白为什么
who treated me so badly was being promoted.
一个待我如此恶劣的人能升迁
I also wondered how long
我也不知道
I would have to endure that man.
我还必须忍受那个男人多久
Then something snapped in me, and I couldn't take it anymore.
然后我心里有了一种冲动 再也忍受不了
I happened to know someone from the editing department at a publishing company
刚好我认识一个出版社编辑部的人
so I asked that person to write the article for me.
就请那个人帮我写了那篇报导
I didn't accept any money.
我没有收钱
I see.
我知道
I thought my voice would be heard
我想如果周刊登出来
if it was published in an article,
我的声音就会被听到
and maybe that would move headquarters to
也许能让总部
make a case out of this.
有足够的理由调查这件事
That's why I sent an email to the President.
所以我才发送电子邮件给总裁
I wanted him to see it before Mr. Omae covered it up.
我想要他在大前先生掩盖真相前看到
But doing this would affect you too, Natsuko…
但是这么做 你也会受影响
I know.
我知道
I don't care what happens to me,
我不在乎我会怎样
as long as I can punish that man.
只要能够让那个男人受到惩罚
I wouldn't have done this,
如果没有做好觉悟
if I wasn't prepared.
我是不会这么做的
So that's what happened.
所以那就是事情始末
Assistant General Manager Omae…
大前次长…
That's horrible.
太过分了
What should I do?
我该怎么做？
Hanasaki.
花琦
Ms. Natsuko Kawashima has been called in.
川岛奈津子小姐
-She'll be here at headquarters tomorrow. -What?
-明天会来总部 -什么？
General Manager Shindo says that he will talk to her.
真藤常务说要和她谈
Can we sit in?
我可以出席吗？
No, you can't.
不行
We've been removed from this case.
我们已经退出这案子了
What?
什么？
They decided that Mr. Shindo and HR will handle it.
他们决定由真藤常务和人事部处理
HR? Then…
人事部？那么
Mr. Omae will be there tomorrow?
明天大前先生会在场？
That's right.
没错
No way.
怎么会这样？
But General Manager Shindo will
可是真藤常务
believe Ms. Kawashima if he hears her story, right?
会相信川岛小姐的说法吧？
He will deal with Mr. Omae accordingly, right?
他会据以处分大前先生 对吧？
-I don't know about that. -What?
-那我就不知道了 -什么？
No matter what she says, Omae will never admit it
不论她说什么 如果没有证据
if there's no proof.
大前都不会承认的
He will probably use any method
他大概会使用各种方法
in order to protect himself.
来保护他自己
I'm sure he'll want to protect himself from
我相信他会不惜一切代价
falling off the promotional ladder at all costs.
不让自己跌落升迁的阶梯
It all depends on who
这都要看真藤先生
Mr. Shindo chooses to believe. Right?
选择相信谁了 对吧？
Then there's a chance that
那么奈津子
Natsuko will be dismissed?
有可能会被开除吗？
Yes.
是
BRANCH MANAGER OMAE
（大前经理来电）
Damn it.
可恶
You're not leaving yet?
你还不下班？
I understand how you feel,
我了解你的感受
but there's nothing you can do.
但是你无能为力
But if Natsuko's the one that ends up getting dismissed,
可是如果最后被开除的是奈津子
what was the point of her doing this…
她做这一切的意义何在？
Sexual and power harassment
性骚扰和权力骚扰很棘手
is troublesome because there's no way to prove it.
因为无法证明
That's why the perpetrator gets bold
所以犯案者才会变本加厉
and repeats the offense.
不断重复犯罪
You're right.
你说的对
Repeats?
重复犯罪
-Oh. -What?
-有了 -什么？
Mr. Soma, can I see the personnel file on Mr. Omae that you were looking at?
相马先生 那张大前先生的个人档案 可以借我看吗？
Here.
给你
He worked in six different branches before going to
他去京桥分行之前
Kyobashi Branch.
待过六间分行
Okay.
好
What?
怎么了？
What are you planning to do?
你想做什么？
I'm going to make a list of female employees
我想列一张在大前手下 做过事的女职员名单
that worked under Mr. Omae and see if they can help us out.
看看她们是否愿意提供情报
What?
什么？
Mr. Soma, you just said that the perpetrator gets bold,
相马先生 你刚刚不是说了吗？ 犯案者会变本加厉
and repeats the offense.
不断重复犯罪
I did but…
我是说了 但是…
There must be more victims that never spoke up.
一定有更多受害者没有说出来
Even if there is, there's no way they would cooperate with us that easily.
就算是那样 她们也不可能轻易与我们合作
I'm still going to try.
我还是要试一试
BRANCH MANAGER KOU OMAE
（分行经理 大前贡）
-Don't push yourself too hard. -Okay.
-别把自己逼得太紧 -好
THE BRANCH MANAGER COMMITTING SEXUAL HARASSMENT IS BRANCH MANAGER OMAE
（犯下性骚扰的经理是大前）
MS. A IS MY COLLEAGUE AND FRIEND
（Ａ小姐是我的同事兼好友）
MY COLLEAGUE AND FRIEND
（我的同事兼好友）
I AM WRITING TO ASK FOR YOUR COOPERATION
（我写这封信是想请求你配合）
No replies.
没有回信
That's to be expected.
果然如此
Mr. Soma isn't here yet.
相马先生还没到
This is four years' worth of documents.
这是四年的人事资料
-Thank you. -No problem.
-谢谢你 -不客气
But I'm surprised that Branch Inspection would work this hard
真没想到稽核班居然会为了一位员工
for one employee.
这么用心
Well…
不
if it was a little while ago
如果是不久之前
I wouldn't have been doing this either.
我也不会做些事
Thanks to my overly passionate subordinate,
多亏了我过度热心的下属
um… how can I say this…
我该怎么说呢？
I can't stay quiet.
我不能默不作声
I see.
原来如此
Natsuko.
奈津子
Mai.
舞
I'm sorry. I tried to see if there was anything I can do, but…
对不起 我想看有没有我能做的 但…
Thank you. Don't worry.
谢谢你 别担心
You must be Natsuko Kawashima.
你一定就是川岛奈津子
-Yes. -Come in.
-是 -进来吧
You have no business here.
这里没有你的事了
You're Natsuko Kawashima from the Kyobashi Branch, right?
你就是京桥分行的川岛奈津子？
-Yes. -Sit down.
-是 -坐吧
Is it true that you are the female employee who is
这个周刊报导背后的那位女职员
behind the story published in this magazine?
就是你 这是真的吗？
Answer us, Kawashima.
回答我们 川岛
Yes.
是
It was me.
就是我
For a long time, I had to
有很长一段时间
put up with sexual harassment from my branch manager.
我不得不忍受分行经理的性骚扰
Kawashima.
川岛
Don't talk nonsense in front of the General Manager.
不要在常务面前胡说八道
By branch manager, you mean Mr. Iwaki?
你说的经理是井胁先生？
No. The previous branch manager.
不是 是前一位经理
It was Mr. Omae sitting right there.
就是坐在这里的大前先生
What?
什么？
What is this about, Mr. Omae?
大前先生 这是怎么回事？
That's ridiculous, I never did such a thing.
太荒谬了 我绝对没做过这种事
She's making everything up.
这都是她捏造的
No! I'm telling the truth!
不 我说的是事实
Believe me. I have never acted inappropriately
相信我 我从来没有对女职员
to a female employee.
做出不当行为
General Manager Shindo, what should we do?
真藤常务 我们该怎么办？
FOUR UNREAD MESSAGES
（四条未读消息）
This is a problem.
这还真棘手
One side is saying that she was sexually harassed,
一方说她受到性骚扰
but the other is denying it.
另一方否认
But with this type of issue, it's always hard to figure out
不过这类纷争一向难以查清
who's telling the truth,
谁说的是实话
unless there is proof.
除非有证据
But what's clear right now is that
但是目前很清楚的是
Kawashima is the whistleblower who
川岛向周刊报导
provided the magazine with a story.
举报此事
And that caused significant damage to
那对东京第一银行的名声
Tokyo Daiichi Bank's reputation.
造成重大伤害
Do you admit to that?
这个你承认吗？
Yes.
是
Kawashima.
川岛
It seems like you're a very competent employee.
你似乎是个很优秀的员工
I don't want to lose a promising employee
我不希望因为这样的事情
over something like this.
失去一位有前途的员工
How about we
这样如何？
pretend this didn't happen?
我们当作这一切不曾发生
Um…
那个…
what do you mean?
这是什么意思？
In other words,
换句话说
Ms. A in this article
周刊中的Ａ小姐
is not you,
不是你
and Bank T
Ｔ银行
is not our bank either.
也不是我们银行
I don't care what happens to me
我不在乎我会怎样
as long as I can punish that man.
只要我能让那个男人受到惩罚
I wouldn't have done this
如果没有做好觉悟
if I wasn't prepared.
我是不会这么做的
You're telling me to forget everything?
你是要我忘掉所有的事？
-But… -This can't continue.
-可是… -如果这件事继续下去
Any more and you will be disgracing all of the 30,000 people
你将会让三万名在这家银行工作的人
working at this bank!
蒙受羞辱
I think my suggestion
我认为我的建议
is the best way to prevent further damage towards
是避免东京第一银行受到进一步伤害
Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
最好的办法
Do you agree?
你同意吗？
Kawashima, what Mr. Shindo says is true.
川岛 真藤常务说的对
Nothing ever happened.
什么事都没有发生过
Everything will be settled, if you say that.
如果你那样说 一切都解决了
It's to benefit the bank.
这是为了银行好
That's okay, right Kawashima?
川岛 这样可以吧？
Please wait a minute.
请等一下
-What are you doing? -Wait…
-你在做什么？ -等等
-Get out. -Hey…
-出去 -等一下
Please take a look at this.
请看一下这个
These are emails from
这些电子邮件
female employees that worked at branches
是之前受大前次长督导的
that Mr. Omae used to oversee.
分行女职员寄来的
"I read that article and immediately knew
“看了那篇报导后 我立刻就知道
that it was about Branch Manager Omae,
文章中说的是大前经理
because he did the same thing to me three years ago."
因为三年前 他对我做过同样的事”
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
These are all lies.
这些都是谎话
"I could not defend myself from Branch Manager's harassment, so I quit
“我无法保护自己 不被大前经理骚扰
the bank a year ago.
一年前 我辞去银行工作
He was very persistent, so I turned him down many times,
他持续了很久 我拒绝他很多次
but he never stopped harassing me."
但是他从不停止骚扰我”
Enough already!
够了
"I couldn't stand Branch Manager Omae's sexual harassment,
“我无法忍受大前经理的性骚扰
so I talked to the chief.
于是我告诉课长
But the branch manager found out
但是经理发现了
and started abusing his authority."
他就开始滥用职权”
General Manager Shindo, I did no such thing!
真藤常务 我没做过这样的事
Believe me.
请相信我
Everyone cooperated because they wanted to
每个人都愿意提供证词 因为她们都想
help out other victims,
帮助别的受害者
and they wanted to punish Assistant General Manager Omae.
而且她们想让大前次长受到惩罚
Enough!
胡说什么？
Anyone can fabricate these things!
谁都能捏造这些东西
Then should we contact these people?
那我们应该联系这些人吗？
What are you saying…
你在说什么？
First of all, there's no way this can be used as proof.
首先 这些不能当作证据
Excuse me.
打扰了
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
I went to Kyobashi Branch
我去了京桥分行
and borrowed Ms. Kawashima's personnel documents.
借来了川岛小姐的个人档案
What?
什么？
Ever since Ms. Kawashima was hired four years ago,
自从川岛小姐四年前被录用之后
she has been receiving high evaluations
她在工作与人品方面
regarding her work and character.
一直受到很高的评价
"Highly valued by boss and colleagues
“受到上司与同事的高度肯定
and has high administrative skills."
具有优秀行政能力”
"An employee essential to our bank."
“是本银行不可多得的员工”
Mr. Omae evaluated her very highly for two years while
大前先生当经理的前两年
he was a branch manager.
给予她高度评价
But when Ms. Kawashima took her
但是去年川岛小姐参加
exam for the general management position last year,
综合管理职的测验时
the letter of recommendation that Mr. Omae wrote was
大前先生写的评价分数
horrible.
不知为何给到最低分
"Behaves badly," "lacks cooperativeness,"
“举止不端”、“不配合”
"problematic with the other sex."
“与异性相处有问题”
Ms. Nakashima's thesis and her interview received passing grades,
川岛小姐的论文与面试成绩都通过了
so the reason why she failed is clearly because of this evaluation.
她失败的原因显然是因为这个评价
Mr. Omae, why did she receive such a low evaluation score this one time?
大前先生 为什么她这次 收到这么低的评价分数呢？
It's inconsistent.
这并不一致
It's…
那是…
because all of those things really happened.
这些事情都真的发生过
I gave an honest assessment.
我给的是公正的评价
With all due respect…
恕我直言
isn't it because
不是因为
you had some kind of trouble with Ms. Kawashima?
你与川岛小姐之间有什么过节吗？
For example, she didn't do as you asked.
例如 她不照你的要求做
In order to take revenge, you gave her a low evaluation score
你为了报复 给她一个很低的分数
so that she would fail her exam.
她因此未通过测验
Am I wrong?
我说错了吗？
Mr. Omae.
大前先生
Natsuko is my friend.
奈津子是我的朋友
Natsuko always said
奈津子总是说
that she enjoyed her work.
她很喜欢她的工作
If she hadn't become your subordinate,
如果她没有成为你的下属
she would still be working with a smile on her face.
她依然会带着微笑工作
Why did she have to become the target
她为什么必须成为
of a despicable boss like you?
你这种卑劣上司的目标？
You messed up her life,
你毁了她的人生
and I will never forgive you for that!
我绝对不原谅你
Hanasaki.
花琦
I will remember what happened here today.
我会记得今天在这里发生的事
Yes.
是
Thank you.
谢谢你们
Mr. Omae will most likely
大前先生最有可能
receive disciplinary action.
受到纪律处分
Yes.
是
But you will also have to take responsibility…
但是你也要负起责任
Don't worry.
不用担心我
I'm prepared to accept any outcome.
我已经准备好接受任何处分了
I see.
我明白
Thanks, Mai.
舞 谢谢你
If you hadn't come in,
要是你没进来
I would have had to agree to their terms.
我会不得不接受他们的条件
I'm so glad I have a friend I can rely on.
有一个能依靠的朋友 真是太好了
I'll be off.
我走了
Natsuko.
奈津子
Yeah?
什么事？
Our hot spring trip.
我们的温泉之旅
The fresh and extravagant seafood platter and the open bath.
新鲜豪华海鲜盘和露天温泉
-Those are a must! -What?
-那些一定要有 -什么？
Did you forget about that? Get it together.
你忘记了吗？振作起来
You're the coordinator.
你是统筹人
-Okay.
-嗯
-See you. -Bye.
-再见 -拜拜
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
You used to look fresh and young too.
你也曾经看起来很年轻又有朝气
Mr. Soma, you're here again?
相马先生 你又来这里了
Any complaints?
不满意吗？
Mai, stop being rude to our precious customer.
舞 不要对我们的贵宾无礼
But I always have to make sure I look
可是我总是得确保我的样子能见人
presentable because my boss can show up anytime.
因为我的上司随时会出现
Don't worry, Hanasaki. I really don't care if you
别担心 花琦 我真的不介意
look presentable or not.
你看起来能不能见人
-Oh, I remembered. -What?
-我想起来了 -什么？
Mr. Soma, you copied me today.
相马先生 你今天学我
What?
什么？
"With all due respect…"
“恕我直言”
I… I didn't copy you…
我没有学你
Everyone uses that phrase.
那个词大家都会用
You can be honest with me.
你可以老实跟我说
I told you that I didn't copy you… I just couldn't resist.
我说了 我不是学你 我只是不小心
Resist? Wait, didn't you ban
不小心？你不是禁止
that word from being used?
使用那个词吗？
You're banned from using it. Not me.
不能说的是你 不是我
Hanasaki.
花琦？
Calm down, you two.
冷静下来 你们两个
This is today's special.
这是今天的特色料理
-Wow! -Thank you.
-哇 -谢谢
Thank you.
我开动了
Delicious!
-好吃
I'm Mai Hanasaki.
我是花琦舞
Maybe we're meant to be.
看来我们是命中注定
Getting illegal money from clients?
收受客户的非法资金？
-I'll stop the wrongdoing. -I don't need to cooperate.
-终止犯罪行为 -我们才不会配合你们
That's the one that accepted the bribe.
那就是收贿款的人
What will happen to my shop?
那我的餐厅要怎么办？
You're wrong as a business manager.
身为企业老板 你做错了